Douglas Robert Cunningham James

Perkeley, CA

→ (916) 802-5609

douglasrcjames@gmail.com

www.douglasrcjames.com



Career Summary:

Web developer with 7+ years of freelance experience, computer technician with 8+ years of experience, and an entrepreneur with a lifelong dream to build great products.

Focused skills: HTML/CSS (7 yrs.), JavaScript /Node.js/React.js (2 yrs.), and Swift (1 yr.)

Education:

San Jose State University

2013 - 2019

Major: Computer Engineering | Minor: Business & Math

San Jose, CA

- Tech: C/C++, Python, MySQL, Swift, Firebase, React.js, and computer hardware & network design
- Member of Computer & Software Engineering Society
- Web Designer & Member for the Pi Kappa Alpha Fraternity

Experience:

Freelance Work

Jun. 2018 - Current (1.5 yrs)

San Jose, CA

- Web Developercapsmd.org
 - Redesigned and coded a Maryland non-profit political publication group's site in under a week (and during finals week).
 - o Continuously adding articles to their site monthly.
 - o 1,000 unique users since launch in Jul. 2019
 - o Tech: HTML/CSS, React.js, Node.js, Firebase, GitHub, Google Analytics
- theretreatonnichols.com
 - Designed, coded, and maintaining site for luxury short-term accommodation in Fairhope,
 Al
 - o 200 unique users since launch in Aug. 2019
 - Tech: HTML/CSS, React.js, Node.js, Firebase, GitHub, Google Analytics
- bodybyyama.com
 - o Designed brand and wireframe with 2 graphic designers for fitness trainer in San Jose.
 - Coded site to match wireframe design.
 - Tech: HTML/CSS, PHP, MySQL, UIKit3
- glasshousefarms.co
 - Designed brand and wireframe with a graphic designer for a hydroponic grow facility in Ithaca, NY.
 - o Coded site to match wireframe design.
 - 3000 unique users since Apr. 2018
 - o Tech: HTML/CSS, PHP, MySQL, UIKit3

Minute.tech LLC 2016 - Current San Jose, CA

- Startup focused on building an on-demand, consumer grade technical support system connecting clients with technicians via messenger, voice/video call, remote connection and inperson scheduling.
- Currently polishing UI & features for web & iOS launch in my free time
- Think of this project as a multi-semester class/internship in business and software development

- Researched and wrote 18-page business plan & 60-page business plan detailing the business opportunity in the technical support space
- Placed top 3 in Shark Tank-like "Silicon Valley Business Plan Competition" awarding \$1500
- Completed wireframe for web app and iOS app
- Built Python, React.js, and Swift prototypes
- Project manager for 15+ individuals throughout 4 SJSU classes
- Personally serviced hundreds of clients on their tech support needs to test the market.
- Secured "Minute.tech" trademark
- Deeper details @ douglasrcjames.com/experience/minute.tech
- **Tech**: HTML/CSS, JS, Node.js, React.js, Redux, Swift, Stripe API, Twilio API, Firebase, Python, Flask framework, MySQL, DigitalOcean, Slack, GitHub, Adobe Creative Suite, InVision

Coldbrew Creative LLC

Winter 2017

Web Developer

San Jose, CA

- Built and managed websites for 10+ clients throughout the Bay Area
- Member of tight knit team of 7 primarily communicating over Slack/Zoom
- Tech: HTML/CSS, JS, PHP, WordPress, SquareSpace, Slack, GitHub

Tesla, Inc.

Product Specialist

Summer/Fall 2016

Santa Clara, CA

Showroom guru educating walk-in clients on Tesla's line of innovative electric vehicles.

- Showborn gurd educating wark-in clients on resid siline of innovative electric vericles
- Test drove prospective clients, stepping them through Tesla features (i.e. Autopilot).
- Persuaded and guided clients in the direct market through building and buying their vehicle.

Palo Alto Networks, Inc.

Summer 2015

IT Specialist

Sunnyvale, CA

- Provided desk technical support to 2000+ employees at the network security firm, Palo Alto Networks (HO)
- Reconciliated 700,000+ company laptops worth over \$350 million
- Taught me how to properly secure networks

ACFN Franchised Inc

Spring 2015

IT Specialist

San Jose, CA

- Remotely supported hundreds of ATM franchisee's technical needs worldwide.
- Troubleshooted various hardware and software issues for 2500+ Triton ATM machines.

iHealPhones Inc. 2010 - 2014

Founder

El Dorado Hills, CA

- Started local phone repair business servicing devices ranging from iPhones to Androids to laptops.
- 80% of work was fixing iPhone screens when iPhones were just hitting the market.
- Venture got my feet wet with hardware/software engineering, business marketing, customer relations, and accounting.

Oak Ridge High School Community Foundation

Winter 2011

Website Developer

El Dorado Hills, CA

• Part of two-man team tasked at designing, building, and managing the organization's website